docker a tool that can package software into containers that run reliably in any
docker是一个可以将软件打包到任何环境中的可靠容器运行工具
environment but what is a container and why do you need one let's imagine you
但是什么是容器以及为什么需要容器，让我们假设您使用cobalt构建了一个应用程序
built an app with cobalt that runs on some weird flavor of linux you want to
该应用程序可以在linux上运行,您想与您的朋友
share this app with your friend but he has an entirely different system so the
分享这个应用程序，你们有两个完全不同的系统
problem becomes how do we replicate the environment our software needs on any
问题变成了我们如何在任何机器上复制我们的软件所需的环境
machine one way to package an app is with a virtual machine where the
打包应用程序的一种方法是使用虚拟机模拟硬件环境
hardware is simulated then installed with the required os and dependencies
然后安装所需的操作系统和相关软件
this allows us to run multiple apps on the same infrastructure however because
这允许我们在同一个基础设施上运行多个应用程序
each vm is running its own operating system they
但是每个虚拟机都运行自己的操作系统
tend to be bulky and slow now a docker container is conceptually
因此它们往往体积庞大且运行速度慢
very similar to a vm with one key difference instead of
与虚拟机非常相似，单有一个关键性区别
virtualizing hardware containers only virtualize the os
那就是虚拟化操作系统，而不是虚拟化硬件容器
or in other words all apps or containers are run by a single kernel
或者换句话说，所有应用程序或容器都在单个内核运行
and this makes almost everything faster and more efficient there are three
这使得几乎所有事情都变得更快、更高效
fundamental elements in the universe of docker
docker宇宙中包含三个基本元素
the docker file the image and the container the docker file is like dna
docker文件、docker镜像、docker容器文件，
it's just code that tells docker how to build an image which itself is a
他们就像DNA只告诉docker如何构建镜像的代码
snapshot of your software along with all of its dependencies down
它是软件快照以及它的所有
to the operating system level the image is immutable and it can be used to spin
对于操作系统级别的依赖，该映像不可变用于启动多个容器
up multiple containers which is your actual software running in the real
这是您在现实世界中运行的实际软件
world create a docker file and use from to
创建一个docker文件并使用
start from an existing template like ubuntu this base image gets pulled down
从现有模板开始,如ubuntu，此基础映从云中像被拉取下来
from the cloud and you can also upload your own images
您还可以将自己的镜像上传到
to a variety of different docker registries
各种不同的docker注册中心中
from there you might want to use run to run a terminal command that installs
您可能希望使用run命令将依赖项安装到镜像中
dependencies into your image you can set environment variables and do
然后您可以设置环境变量并执行其他各种命令
all kinds of other stuff then the last thing you'll do is set a default command
你要做的最后一件事是设置一个在
that's executed when you start up a container
启动容器时执行的默认命令
and now we can create the image file by running the docker build command
现在我们可以通过运行 docker build 命令来创建镜像文件
it goes through each step in our docker file to build the image layer by layer
它通过我们的docker文件中的每个步骤逐层构建映像
we can then bring this image to life as a container with the docker run command
然后我们可以使用 docker run 命令将该映像作为容器赋予生命
as your app demands more resources you can run it on multiple machines multiple
当您的应用程序需要更多资源时
clouds on-prem or wherever you want reliably this has
您可以在多台云服务上运行它
been docker in 100 seconds if you enjoyed it make sure to like and
如果您确定喜欢它
subscribe and stay tuned for more docker content coming to this channel soon
请订阅并继续关注更多docker内容
thanks for watching and i will see you in the next one
感谢您的收看，下次见